<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[My Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Whatever I want it to be]]></description><link>https://charlesarnaudo.github.io/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 22:02:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Second Post]]></title><description><![CDATA[Another week, more NPM mishaps. Javascript is the worst and I hate it. Making this websites has got me thinking more about the requirements…]]></description><link>https://charlesarnaudo.github.io//second_post/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://charlesarnaudo.github.io//second_post/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Another week, more NPM mishaps. Javascript is the worst and I hate it. Making this websites has got me thinking more about the requirements
for our project, specifically the UI. I’ve also been reading a lot of &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Why Software Sucks&lt;/code&gt;, in which the beginning chapters are about UI. With
this in mind, I think the UI for our application should be served by a webpage. It should be simple, like really &lt;strong&gt;simple&lt;/strong&gt;. No dumb stuff, or
frameworks. Just some input fields and maybe display current counts. I want it to be dumb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worry a bit about people on the team getting carried away and going to fast with the project. The longer we wait to code the better and simpler
our app will be. IMO if this app is anything over ~1500 lines of code we messed up.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[First Post]]></title><description><![CDATA[My goals for this week were to iron out the kinks in my deploy process for this blog and connect with my team to start discussion on…]]></description><link>https://charlesarnaudo.github.io//first-post/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://charlesarnaudo.github.io//first-post/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;My goals for this week were to iron out the kinks in my deploy process for this blog and connect with my team to start discussion on requirements for our project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a tool called Gatsby to build this site. It’s dependices are managed through &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;npm&lt;/code&gt;, which is almost definitely the worst package manager in the world. Somehow
Gatsby itself got removed from the dependcy list so my deploys weren’t working all week. I had to dig through git commits to find it had been removed. I’ve decided to
learn more about &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;npm&lt;/code&gt; that way this doesn’t happen again. I did not anticipate having these issues with the blog but I was able to resolve them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our teams were just finalized yesterday, so I’ve reached out to a few people in the group to talk about requirements.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>